Contact

+55 (11) 96888-4933 (Mobile) byfabioalencar@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ fabioalencaresouza (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

UX

Frontend

Project Management

Languages

Spanish (Elementary)

Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

EF SET English Certificate 79/100 (C2 Proficient)

Design System & Ops

Certified ScrumMaster® (CSM®)

Honors-Awards

Second Place: STAND SHOW APAS – POPAI 2018 | Category: Best Promotional Action - Medium Size

First Place: STAND SHOW APAS – POPAI 2019 | Category: Best Promotional Action - Medium Size

Fábio Alencar

Product Design Lead | Tech Lead | Entrepreneuer | Braintrust Founding Member

São Paulo

Summary

Entrepreneur and team leader for 8 years. Creative Technologist, Product Designer and Frontend Developer. Post-graduated by ESPM in Marketing and Digital Design. Certified ScrumMaster® (CSM®). Studying Software Engineering at FIAP. Experienced and passionate about the whole process of building digital products. Specialist in the convergence between business, design and technology.

Experience

Trinks.com

Product Design Lead

August 2020 - Present (6 months)

Biggest marketplace of beauty services in Brazil. More than 700k B2C users and 50k B2B users.

Since 2019 part of Stone Group, a payment processing services unicorn.

Responsabilities:

- Collaborate with business, product management, UX designers and engineering partners to lead and develop product and design strategies.
- Advocate for the user, and drive a holistic UX vision that inspires the team to push on the status quo.
- Explore product concepts to find promising directions that address both human and business needs.
- Build prototypes to assist in user research, using low to high-fidelity techniques.
- Support multiple projects simultaneously while meeting tight deadlines.
- Advise front-end engineers on UI implementation best practices.
- Facilitate collaboration between teams and individuals to evolve the needs of the product alongside the design system.

Interativ - Agência Digital Tech Lead, UI/UX Lead

January 2016 - August 2020 (4 years 8 months)

São Paulo, Brazil

- Problem solver based in user needs and high performance.
- · Team management.
- Project management.
- Tech lead in UI/UX Development.
- · Sales of digital solutions.
- Javascript Development (Node, Express, Angular, React, Gatsby, Ionic and API integrations).
- · PHP, Wordpress, Drupal.
- MySQL, Postgres, mongodb, Redis.
- · Integration with rest APIs and GraphQL.

Devign | Soluções em apresentações Cofounder Business Development February 2012 - July 2020 (8 years 6 months) São Paulo

High Impact Presentations.

Universidade Veiga de Almeida (UVA) - Whitney International Fullstack Developer, Creative Technologist March 2013 - May 2015 (2 years 3 months)

Tijuca, Rio de Janeiro

- Frontend Development (HTML, CSS, Javascript/Jquery).
- Backend Development (PHP, Wordpress, MySQL, Drupal).
- Marketing technologist: Intermediary between Marketing and IT team.
- UI/UX Design

Freelance

Creative Technologist January 2008 - July 2014 (6 years 7 months)

- UI/UX.
- Frontend development (HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, React and Angular).
- · Website design and development.
- CMS maintenance and customization (Drupal and Wordpress).
- Search Engine Optimization (SEO).
- Planning and execution of digital marketing campaigns (Email, Analytics and SEM).

M2BRNET.com

Frontend Developer

April 2011 - May 2012 (1 year 2 months)

Rio de Janeiro Area, Brazil

- Front-End Development (HTML / CSS / JQuery).
- Design of interfaces, newsletters and banners.
- Animation and programming in Action Script 2.0.
- Maintenance, customization and creation of templates for CMS Wordpress.
- Creation of responsive websites and applications with HTML5, CSS3, JQuery and Phonegap.

Skidun Interactive Agency

Frontend Developer

November 2010 - April 2011 (6 months)

- Front-End Development (HTML / CSS / JQuery).
- Information architecture.
- Maintenance, customization and creation of templates for CMS Wordpress.
- Development of newsletters.

Criapix

Jr. Frontend Developer and Web Designer August 2007 - November 2010 (3 years 4 months)

- UI design / Motion Design
- Frontend development (HTML, CSS, JQuery)

Education

FIAP

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Software Engineering \cdot (2020 - 2021)

Escola Superior de Propaganda e Marketing

Master of Business Administration - MBA, Digital Marketing and Design · (2011 - 2013)

Universidade Veiga de Almeida

Master of Business Administration - MBA - Incomplete, Project Management · (2014 - 2015)

Estácio

Design, Graphic · (2007 - 2009)